(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-09T10:09:21.594795",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
カレーメシ スパイスライフ カレーメシWEEK
Curry Meshi: Spice Life - Curry Meshi WEEK
日清カレーメシ
Nissin Curry Meshi
ラララ ラララ イェイ イェイ イェイ
La la la, la la la, yeah, yeah, yeah!
ラララ ラララ
La la la, la la la...
Come on!
みんな見てるカー？
Are you all watching?
スパイスライフ盛り上げていくっすよ！
We're gonna hype up this Spice Life!
調子はどう？そこそこな感じ？
How's it going? Feeling okay?
満たしてないのにニコニコりあんず
Smiling even though you're unsatisfied, aliens!
1分ずつ1分ずつまとめて ぐるぐるる
One minute at a time, gathering it all, round and round!
どっちらけ？
Feeling awkward?
スパイス収入 昨日のハートかきまぜちゃお
Spice income, let's stir up yesterday's heart!
そしたらきっと楽しいキミの出来上がり
Then you'll surely have your fun self ready!
ほんの少しだけでもアタシらノーサンキュー！
Even just a bit? No thank you!
スローライフでねずっけタッチゃう？
Shall we touch it in a slow life?
心豊かに ファイ！オー！ピース！ワン！
Rich in heart! Phi! Oh! Peace! One!
本当に美味いぜカレーメシ 絶対に本気味の化け物
Truly delicious Curry Meshi, an absolute monster of serious flavor!
1分ずつ1分ずつ美味しく頂戴して満たしましょい
One minute at a time, let's deliciously savor and get filled up!
どんなスープ混ぜたら広がるパラダイス
What kind of soup should we mix to spread paradise?
食べたい食べたい食べたいのよ 美味しい！じゃない、最高です！
I want to eat it! It's delicious! No, it's the best!
日清カレーメシ ジャスティス！
Nissin Curry Meshi Justice!
たっぷりのしじみ観てもらえると嬉しいです！今日のライブもたくさん盛り上げてほしいな！
We'd be so happy if you check out the shijimi clams! Hope you enjoy today's live to the fullest!
最近のこう
Lately, like,
ついてない感じ どん底こそ隠し味のスパイス
unlucky feelings, rock bottom is the hidden spice
そっからさっさ全部始めよう
Let's start all over right from there
ぐるぐるる トキメキピピピッ
Round and round, heartbeat pipippi
カラフルでもたまには甘えさせてね そしたらきっとつらくたって乗り切れちゃう
Even if colorful, let me act spoiled sometimes. Then you'll surely get through even the tough times
まあへこんでてもうわんわんのサンキュー！
Well, even if you're down, bow-wow thank you!
ナレーターでレス金がさー
Fan service as a narrator is like,
心踊らせ ファイ！オー！シーツーワン！
Makes your heart dance! Phi! Oh! C2-1!
本当に美味いぜカレーメシ
Truly delicious Curry Meshi,
絶対に本気味の化け物
an absolute monster of serious flavor!
1分ずつ1分ずつ美味しく頂戴して満たしましょい
One minute at a time, let's deliciously savor and get filled up!
どんなスープ混ぜたら広がるパラダイス
What kind of soup should we mix to spread paradise?
食べたい食べたい食べたいのよ 美味しい！じゃない、最高です！
I want to eat it! It's delicious! No, it's the best!
日清カレーメシ ジャスティス！
Nissin Curry Meshi Justice!
みんな まだまだ盛り上がれる世界よ！ 最後まで来てね！
Everyone, the world can get even more hyped! Stay until the end!
ラララ ラララ イェイ イェイ イェイ
La la la, la la la, yeah, yeah, yeah!
心豊かに ファイ！
Rich in heart! Phi!
スパイス聞き分けて頑張りましょい
Let's distinguish the spices and do our best!
出会いは無限の宝物
Encounters are infinite treasures
1歩ずつ 1歩ずつさー
Step by step, step by step,
ームハットの絵を抜けて行きましょい
Let's get through the paintings of the hat!
本当に美味いぜカレーメシ
Truly delicious Curry Meshi,
絶対に本気味の化け物
an absolute monster of serious flavor!
1分ずつ 1分ずつさー
One minute at a time, one minute at a time,
美味しく頂戴して満たしましょい
let's deliciously savor and get filled up!
どんなスープ混ぜたら広がるパラダイス
What kind of soup should we mix to spread paradise?
食べたい食べたい食べたいのよ 美味しい！じゃない、最高です！
I want to eat it! It's delicious! No, it's the best!
日清カレーメシ ジャスティス！ スパイスを新たに ポジティブを新たに 日清カレーメシ ジャスティス！
Nissin Curry Meshi Justice! New spices, new positivity, Nissin Curry Meshi Justice!
はい！ということで、
Yes! So,
日清カレーメシかけるホロライブのコラボレーション企画、
Nissin Curry Meshi x Hololive's collaboration project,
スパイスライブが始まりましたー！
Spice Live has begun!
はい、ということでね、可愛すぎるとか、
Yes, so, she's too cute,
おまじないしてくれてるとか、ありがとうございます！
casting a spell for us, thank you!
もうね、ジャスティスからね、始まりましたけど、
Well, it started with Justice,
ジャスティスね、どう、どうでしたから、もう息も絶えだいですけれども、
Justice, how, how was it? We're already out of breath, though.
ちょっとね、この1週間ね、あのカレーメシとのコラボをさせていただきました！
For the past week, we've had a collaboration with Curry Meshi!
スパイス！
Spice!
ラブイ！
Love!
あ、じゃあリスこおねがいします！ お願いします！ お願いします！
Ah, then listeners, please! Please! Please!
はい、ということでですね、10月1日からですね、本日18日まで行われた全体にものやりすぎコラボ、カレーメシウィークですが、ついに
Yes, so, from October 1st to today the 18th, the overall "over-the-top" collaboration, Curry Meshi Week, finally...
最後の、最後のステージということでね！
As the final, final stage!
もうね、今日でね、最後になります。でもね、うん、ま、今日のコラボレーションのアンバサダーとして選ばれた私たち、
Today is the final day. But, you know, as the ambassadors chosen for today's collaboration,
スパイスラブによるライブパフォーマンスステージは始まったばかり！
our live performance stage by Spice Love has just begun!
はい、ライブの感想はTwitterのハッシュタグ
Yes, your thoughts on the live can be posted with the Twitter hashtag
はい！これですね、アクトの上に、これえ、カレーメシ、カレーメシスパイスライブでね、ぜひね、たくさんツイートしてください！お願いします！お願いします！
Yes! This one, above Act, this, er, Curry Meshi Spice Live, please tweet a lot! Please! Please!
と言うことでですね、オープニングの曲にお送りしたのは、2018年！日清カレーメシとアイドルマスター シンデレラガールズによるコラボレーション楽曲、「スパイスパラダイス カレーメシver.」でしたー！イェーイ！やったー！
So, the opening song we delivered was the 2018 collaboration song between Nissin Curry Meshi and THE IDOLM@STER CINDERELLA GIRLS, "Spice Paradise (Curry Meshi Ver.)"! Yay! Woohoo!
あ、ということでですね、えーアイドルマスター シンデレラガールズを改めてご紹介するのですが、
So, er, I'd like to introduce THE IDOLM@STER CINDERELLA GIRLS again.
2011年にサービスを開始したアイドルマスターシリーズのソーシャルゲームで、
It's a social game in THE IDOLM@STER series that launched in 2011.
お、そうそう、みゅ、知ってる知ってる知ってるぺこ、知ってる！
Oh right, I know, I know, I know, Peko, I know!
ということで、プレイヤーがプロデューサーになって、自身のプロデュースするアイドルをトップアイドルへと育成するアイデームス、あ、アイドルゲームで、登場アイドルはなんと！190人以上、いっぱいいるよ！
So, players become producers and train idols they produce into top idols, an idol game where there are over 190 idols! There are so many!
ていうアイドルが多数登場する人気のゲーム！アイドルマスター シンデレラガールズ スターライトステージは、今年の9月で5周年を迎えたんだよ！おめでとう！
A popular game featuring many such idols! THE IDOLM@STER CINDERELLA GIRLS Starry Stage celebrated its 5th anniversary this September! Congratulations!
そして次のは、ハロウィンにぴったりのイベントも近日開催予定ということでぺこ、この詳細は公式Twitterやゲーム内のお知らせをチェックしてくださいぺこ！
And next, an event perfect for Halloween is coming soon, so Peko, please check the official Twitter and in-game notices for details, Peko!
そして、2018年のカレーメシコラボでは、この曲に加えて3次元さんの制作のハイクオリティなCGアニメ、CGアニメも話題になったんだよ！
And, in the 2018 Curry Meshi collaboration, in addition to this song, high-quality CG anime produced by Sanzigen also became a hot topic!
なんとよ！みんな見た？見た見た見た、めちゃくちゃぬるぬるで、ね、ほんとにさ、ゴリゴリしてるみたいだったよね、すごい！ねえ、あれね、ぜひねみんなもね見てください！
Really! Did everyone see it? Saw it, saw it, saw it, it was so smooth, you know, it really looked like it was in 3D/solid motion, amazing! Hey, everyone, definitely go check it out!
これね、無言でね、ポジション替えがどんどん行われていくんですけど、はい、ということで、私たちも大先輩に一歩でも近づけるように、まあねアイドル活動を頑張っていこうね！
This, silently, positions keep changing one after another, so yes, so that we can get even a step closer to our great seniors, let's keep working hard on our idol activities!
ということで、改めてスパイスラブとしての自己紹介をさせていただきます！よろしくお願いします！
So, once again, let us introduce ourselves as Spice Love! Thank you!
いや、みんなね、3人初めてだけど、息合わせていくよ！オッケーぺこ！何々何だったっけ？
Well, everyone, the three of us are together for the first time, but we'll get in sync! Okay Peko! What, what was it again? What was it?
スパイスラブ！黄色担当、大空スバル！よろしくお願いします！
Spice Love! Yellow rep, Oozora Subaru! Nice to meet you!
ということは、スパイスライブに参戦、スパイスラブみんなピンク担当！イェーイ！よろしくお願いします！
That means, participating in the Spice Live, Spice Love, everyone pink rep! Yay! Nice to meet you!
ということは、なんだろう、歩き方の貫禄が、生活、ペコペコペコ、ちょっとマジで、スパイスラブ緑色、そして人参担当このライブの参戦な
That means, I wonder, the dignity of walking, lifestyle, Peko peko peko, seriously, Spice Love green, and carrot rep, participating in this live...
さあ、ペコラペコラ！
Now, Pekora, Pekora!
今日もね、可愛い！
Today too, you're so cute!
ほら、もうニンジンだとも認めたんだね。
See, you've already admitted you're a carrot.
もう、だって！
Well, because!
だってね！
Because, you know!
だっ……だってね！
Because... because, you know!
色々あったもんね！色々あったもんなぁ！
A lot happened, didn't it! A lot happened!
ていうか、今日ペコラニンジンなんだね。
I mean, Pekora's a carrot today.
全然だ！
Not at all!
全然めしを、今日はちょっとカレーメシぶっささってたけどさ。
Curry Meshi is really stuck in today, though.
あのニンジン返してもらった方がいいのかな。今日のね。
Should I get that carrot back? Today's, I mean.
今日、取り上げられてたの？
Was it confiscated today?
そう、今までニンジン取り上げられてさ……
Yeah, up until now, my carrots were taken away...
冷凍保存の食べ物になっちゃってさ！
And I became frozen preserved food!
ほら、カレーメシってみんなももう食べてるってことじゃん。大人になるってことはさ。
Look, Curry Meshi means everyone's already eating it. Growing up means that.
食べる前、食べる前、食べる前、食べる前に、直前に！シクシクシクシク泣いちゃうからさ！
Before eating, right before eating, I cry my eyes out!
それはヤバイ！ニンジンにね！
That's terrible! For a carrot!
なるべくなら、カレーメシを食べたいんだ！
If possible, I want to eat Curry Meshi!
そういうことか！だからめちゃめちゃ意識高いじゃん。
Is that so? That's why you're so high-conscious.
だってさ、みんなに、音が鳴るからさ、チャカチャカチャカ！
Because sounds ring out to everyone, clatter clatter!
まぁね、今日はね、あの意識の高いペコラと、ダークあくあくのさ！
Well, today, with the high-conscious Pekora and Dark Aqua!
スパイシーなね、3人でね、頑張っていきたいと思います！
We three spicy ones will do our best!
お願いします！
Please!
ニンジンやっぱり落ち着くなって。お湯を入れた状態で踊るペコラって。
Carrots really make me feel calm. Pekora dancing with hot water added.
あっ、ヤバイ、ヤバイ！ボリュームあるからね、あれボリュームあると。
Ah, dangerous! It has volume, so if it has volume...
え、ところでさ、1曲目ね終わったんですけどね。
Um, by the way, the first song is over.
フリップとかさ、どうだったよ、マジで！
What about the flips, seriously?!
すごく可愛かった！
It was so cute!
だっ……だってさ、あそこめっちゃ楽しくない？
Because, you know, wasn't that place super fun?
うまっ！まじでうまかった！
Delicious! Seriously delicious!
ここ、ここ！レコメンド。お隣があるからね。
Here, here! Recommended. Because there's a neighbor.
出さなきゃいけないんだよね。
We have to put it out.
これね、もうめちゃめちゃね、やっててもろいんだよね、これ。
This is super fragile even when doing it.
他なんかありますか？あくたん。
Is there anything else, Aqua?
やっぱフレッシュ。
As expected, fresh.
これ！ジャスティスゼロレコメンドやっぱりカレーメシダンスジャスティスは！
This! Justice Zero Recommend after all Curry Meshi Dance Justice!
カレーメシの、リッキーのCMとかでもすごく使ってるもんくなんだよ。
It's heavily used in Curry Meshi's Ricky commercials too.
名誉あるフリップなんですよ。
It's an honorable flip.
なんかでもやってておもろいです。
But it's fun to do.
ペコラはさ、スーパーイースをお手伝いに
Pekora, helping with Super Spice
最後ね、ここね、なかなかね、体から抜けなくてね、ここ。
Finally, here, it's hard to get out of the body, here.
これね、みんなとこあるからさ。
Because everyone's here.
みんなちょっとさ、何があったところとかあった？
Did anyone have places where something happened?
あとは今日はね、なんつね、めちゃめちゃ、今だにだけど、アイドル衣装なんですよ！
Also today, how should I say, even now, it's an idol costume!
しかも3人ともデザインが違うんだよね。そう、違う！そうなんだよ。
And all three of us have different designs. Right, different! That's right.
ペコラはさ、なんかその、背中が！
Pekora, like, her back!
布がないじゃん！ペコラが一番布がない！
There's no fabric! Pekora has the least fabric!
まぁね、こんな感じでね、今日はね、スパイスもね、鮮やかにやっていきたいと思います！
Well, like this, today we want to do spice brightly too!
でも全部かわいかったって。うれしい。あきるとにもいっしょってどういうことだよ！
But they said it was all cute. I'm happy. What do you mean "together with Akiru"?
ありがと、ありがとね。セクシー担当って言われてる。
Thank you, thank you. Called the sexy representative.
アイドルみたいだぞってアクはよかったね。ありがと！可愛い！
"You look like idols," Aqua was good. Thank you! Cute!
あとはアクはさ、なんかさ、髪の毛とかさ、リボンもさ、ふわふわしてすごく可愛いの。
Also Aqua, like, her hair and ribbons are fluffy and super cute.
ありがとう！これからもよろしくね！なんだお前！
Thank you! Keep treating me well! What are you!
はい、ということでそろそろね、次の曲行っちゃいますか！
Yes, with that, shall we head to the next song soon!
歌いましょう！次のね、披露したいと思います。皆さんね、ポジションについてくださいよ。
Let's sing! We'd like to show the next one. Everyone, please get into position.
ここだ。はい、いいですか？
Here. Yes, is that good?
ちょっと今、汗かいて。
Sweating a bit now.
あせかいてるからね。やばいよね。
Because I'm sweating. It's dangerous.
それでは皆さん！続いては、コンビランドさ、コラボレーション楽曲、「輝いて！」
Now everyone! Next is Combiland collaboration song, "Shine!"
カレーなる新化の果てに
At the end of curry's evolution
カレーは辿り着いた
Curry has finally arrived
お湯さえあれば奇跡の味
Just add hot water for a miraculous taste
食卓照らせ
Illuminate the dining table
カレーメシ ワンワンワン
Curry Meshi Wan Wan Wan
即席とあなどる目で見せてた
With eyes that looked down on it as mere instant food,
メガネはもう捨てたの
I've already thrown away those glasses.
食卓に天の川をかけた
I built the Milky Way right on the dining table!
一口ほかにはないから
Because there's no other single bite like it!
焦らずよく混ぜて
Don't rush, mix it up well,
じれったさに負けないで
Don't lose to the impatience—
液体感が消えたなら
once the liquid feeling vanishes,
本格派で最新だけどカレー
it's authentic and cutting-edge, yet it's curry!
まろみがあり奥深くて あと引くスパイシー
Mellow yet deep, with a lingering spice,
なのに超簡単にできて
yet so super easy to make!
国産米を使っている ちゃんと知ってる？
Using domestic rice—do you properly know that?
至福のカレーメシ ぐるぐるとかき混ぜよ
Supreme Curry Meshi, stir it round and round!
銀河がうずまくように まぜ尽くせ
Stir it up completely so the galaxy swirls!
グルメほど うなり上げるジャスティスジャスティス 食べよう
Like true gourmets, let's shout "Justice! Justice!" and eat!
2秒にいっこのペースで売れている
Selling at a pace of one every two seconds!
確かナンデスタね 明日には国民食へ
That's right, isn't it? Tomorrow it becomes the national food!
新生誕生 イライの マスパーピスを 食べた あなたの 世界は 変わる
A new birth—the masterpiece of elation. The world of whoever eats it changes!
やがて 人は 月まで たどり着いて カレーは お湯で作る 時が来た
Eventually humans will reach the moon, and the time has come to make curry with hot water!
国籍も無く 運命に出会された
Without even a nationality, brought together by destiny,
カレーがもつ 可能性を そこからは 信じた 結晶
believe in the potential that curry holds—from there is the crystallized truth.
まるで 全文明の 証に
As if a proof of all civilizations,
どんな 時も これさえ あれば お腹満足
no matter what time, as long as we have this, our stomachs are satisfied!
カレーメシ 日になにも 聞きょうじも この世の 恵み 感じて 焦がれて
Curry Meshi, feeling the blessings of this world and yearning,
喜びを 楽しめよ ジャスティスジャスティス うまいぞ
enjoy the joy! Justice! Justice! It's delicious!
お湯かけて 五分かけて 蓋をあけて
Pour hot water, take five minutes, open the lid,
とろみがつくまで かき混ぜよ 召し上がれ まさしく カレー
stir until it gets thick and rich, dig in, truly Curry!
クセになる ジャスティスジャスティス うまいぞ
It's addictive! Justice! Justice! It's delicious!
カレーメシ
Curry Meshi!
はい、という事で
Yes, and with that,
いらっしゃいました！2019年のカレーメシと『オラのテレビアニメゾンビランドサガ』のコラボレーション楽曲「カレーメシ・イン・ミラクル」輝いていましたね！
welcome! The collaboration song "Curry Meshi in Miracle" from 2019's Curry Meshi and the TV anime Zombieland Saga shone so brightly!
いかがでしたか皆さん
How was it, everyone?
どうぞどっちだったかちょっとコメントのね皆さんパチパチありがとうございます！
Thank you very much for all the clapping comments in chat!
曲と歌詞のなんか感じが みんなねなんか気付いてくれてたみたいだね！
It seems like everyone noticed the vibe between the song and the lyrics!
そうなんか歌詞がカレーメシバージョンになってて ドキドキしましたけれど！
Yeah, the lyrics were a Curry Meshi version, so it made our hearts race!
でも結構珍しくというか結構エモーショナルな曲なんで歌う時もドキドキしましたけど
But since it's a rather rare, emotional song, we were nervous singing it too!
ここでねアクアの方からゾンビランドサガの紹介をお願いします！
Now Aqua-chan, please introduce Zombieland Saga for us!
はい、分かりました！ということで！
Yes, understood! So!
ゾンビランドサガは、ゾンビとなった女の子たちが佐賀県を舞台にトップアイドルを目指す笑いあり涙ありの新感覚ゾンビアイドル系アニメになってます！
Zombieland Saga is a new-sense zombie idol anime where girls who have become zombies aim to become top idols set in Saga Prefecture, filled with laughter and tears!
そうなの！でね、なかなか奇抜なストーリーなんだけれども、舞台が佐賀県であることから大きな話題を呼んでいて、今作に登場するアイドルグループの「フランシュシュ」っていう…フランシュシュ…？フランシュシュ…！声優メンバーが…
That's right! It's a rather quirky story, but because it's set in Saga Prefecture, it's drawn a lot of attention, and the idol group appearing in this work called "Franchouchou"... Franchouchou...? Franchouchou...! The voice actor members...
佐賀県PR大使に選ばれるなど、幅広い活躍を見せているんで、
They've been chosen as Saga Prefecture PR ambassadors
そうなんですよ。そうなんです。
and are showing a wide range of activities. That's right.
そして、これの続きはこっち！ お願いします！
And the continuation of this is over here! Please take a look!
そんなコラボでは、テレビアニメのスタッフが勢ぞろいしたコラボムービーのほかに、
In this collaboration, besides the collaboration movie featuring the full anime staff,
スパイシーラブのコラボ曲「カレーメシ・イン・ミラクル」を制作してくれた
they produced the Spicy Love collaboration song 'Curry Meshi in Miracle'.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
なんか、曲の雰囲気はね、なんかまったく違ってたよね。そうだね。はい！
The atmosphere of the song was really totally different. That's right. Yes!
そして、アクタン！はい！そしてね、現在続編のゾンビランドサガリベンジも制作中なんですよー！
And, Akutan! Yes! And currently, the sequel Zombie Land Saga Revenge is in production!
それも、それも！そして視聴者の皆さんもち、ゾンビランドサガの応援をどうぞよろしくお願いします！
That too, that too! And everyone watching, please continue to support Zombie Land Saga!
お願いします！面白いからぜひ見てね。
Please do! It's interesting, so definitely check it out.
で、アクタンにさ、おすすめポイント聞きたい。
And, I want to ask Akutan for her recommended points.
あのね、すごい、あの、初めて見た、ギャグなの？ギャグなんだよ。
Well, it's amazing, um, the first time I saw it, is it a gag? It's a gag.
ええ！？ゾンビランドサガなのに？
Eh!? Even though it's Zombie Land Saga?
なのに泣けるんだよね。なんか最初、お、かわいい女の子がいる、
Even so, it makes you cry. At first, you're like, Oh, there are cute girls,
見てみたら、えっ！？ってなるの。最初一話で。一話でえっ！？ってなるの。
and when you watch it, you're like, Huh!? In the very first episode. In the first episode, you're like, Huh!?
え、初っ端から衝撃展開を迎えて、
Eh, it hits you with a shocking development right from the start,
なんか最初、えっ、あ、こういう感じ？みたいな感じなんだけど、すごい、私は結構ツボがそのゾンビランドサガにあってて、すごい面白くて、
and at first you're like, Eh, ah, is this the kind of vibe? But it really hit my funny bone, Zombieland Saga was super funny,
時には泣けるんですよ、これが。ねっ！？ねっ！？泣いてしまった。
and sometimes you cry, this. Right!? Right!? I ended up crying.
アクタンね、そういうエモいの好きだからね。大好きだから。じゃあ笑いあり、エモいありなんだ。
Akutan likes emotional stuff like that. She loves it. So there's laughter and emotion.
ありです！ありありありいただきました。
Yes! We got a lot of 'Yes'.
面白かったね。じゃあまずみんなね、一話から見てみるってね。おっ！がんばってね。
It was funny. So everyone, watch it starting from episode 1. Oh! Do your best.
紹介上手にお世話になります、アクタン。アニメのことならおまかせよ。ありがとうございまーす！本当に、有益な情報を有難うございます。はい！
Thanks for the great introduction, Akutan. Leave anime to us. Thank you very much! Thank you truly for the useful information. Yes!
で、ではですね、じゃあここであ改めてね、スパルタンの方からね、ちょっとね、カレーメシの方に紹介してもいいですか？はい！じゃあ紹介しましょう！はい！
Well then, let's reintroduce it, from Spartan, can we introduce Curry Meshi? Yes! Let's introduce it! Yes!
ということでですね、日清カレーメシは、カップにお湯を注いで5分経ったら、ぐるぐるぐるぐるカレーと絡めるだけ！混ぜて！混ぜて！混ぜて！
So, Nissin Curry Meshi is just pouring hot water into the cup, waiting 5 minutes, and stirring it around with the curry! Mix it! Mix it! Mix it!
ということでですね、ちゃんと、カレーが楽しめる手軽さと美味しさに高評価をいただいております。ちゃんと、美味しさのその秘密は、ごろっと入ってるルー！
So, it has received high praise for its ease and deliciousness, allowing you to properly enjoy curry. The secret to its deliciousness is the chunky roux!
そして、カレーメシのルーにはカレーを美味しくするコリアンダーやカルダモンなどのスパイス、そして玉ねぎの！
And, the Curry Meshi roux contains spices like coriander and cardamom that make the curry delicious, and onions!
玉ねぎの甘みが詰まっている！
The sweetness of onions is packed in!
もう、自ら、自らね！だってやれって空気に、強制的にさ！だって気になっちゃうじゃん！
You know, voluntarily, voluntarily! Because you're forced into the mood to do it! Because you get curious!
だからね、普通に美味しいカレーができあがるんです。
That's why a normally delicious curry gets made.
はい。はい。そんなカレーメシを、ええとですね、イメージして出来上がったですね、カレーメシ専用ステージが、実はですね、あるんですけど、いろんなギミックが詰まってるんです！
Yes. Yes. There is actually a Curry Meshi dedicated stage imagined from such Curry Meshi, and it's packed with various gimmicks!
それでは、こちらの、えーと、ご覧ください。
Well then, please take a look at this.
これね、昨日ね、あの、一緒にね、あのね、カレーメシを食べたカレーメシ組もいるんですけど、あっ、後ろ見てください、こちら！
This, yesterday, um, some of the Curry Meshi group who ate Curry Meshi together are here too, ah, look behind you, here!
あっ、ちょっとカレーメシを横に寄ってもらって、ちょっと正面に映って。
Ah, move Curry Meshi a bit to the side, and show it right in front.
めっちゃめちゃ正面で。これね、後ろのカレーメシが、あ、悪と、なんかモルサランってね、これね、ここでおっきく見えるってことだ。
Right in front. This, the Curry Meshi in the back, ah, Aku and, like Morsaran, you can see it big here.
そうそうそう。そしてですね、右ではね、スプーンがぐるぐるぐるぐる回って、ちゃんとね、お湯も注いでたかね。
That's right, that's right. And on the right, the spoon is spinning around and around, and it also poured hot water.
そうなんだ、そうなんだ。で、ぐるぐる混ぜて、で、カレーメシができあがると、で、あと、手前のライトも全部カレーメシなんですね、あれ。
That's right, that's right. And it mixes around, and when the Curry Meshi is ready, and also, the lights in front are all Curry Meshi, aren't they?
あ、ほら、手前のライトもかわいい。すっごいカレーメシが全部ついてます。
Ah, look, the lights in the front are cute too. Super Curry Meshi is attached all over.
そしてですね、後ろには、あのね、ペコラちゃんのニンジン！そして、左側の温泉から本日届きました、採れたてです！
And then, in the back, um, Pekora-chan's carrots! And, freshly delivered today from the hot springs on the left!
そして、隣には、みなとんのジョージも、なんと、のって、おかしいてしょって！
And next to it, Minaton's George is also on it, isn't it strange!
それではですね、ぜひ後ろのステージにも注目して、ライブを楽しんでください！
Well then, please pay attention to the stage in the back as well and enjoy the live!
ちょっと今何があったのか わっ！
Wait, what just happened? Ah!
じゃあ ちょっと三人で どうする？ ジャスティスって…
So, let's three of us... What should we do? If we do "Justice"...
せーの！ ジャスティス！
Ready, set, Justice!
うわあ！ハイテンション！ すごいすごい！
Whoa! High energy! Amazing, amazing!
これね、こういうのもね こだわりの深い…何を見てるんですか？
And you know, even things like this... deep dedication... What are you looking at?
後ろから、うん。
From behind, yeah.
流れ星みたいな…
Like shooting stars...
何を見てるんですか、せめて後ろから空いてるけど… 空いてる紹介なんだよ、いま。
What are you looking at? At least from behind it's open... We're introducing what's open right now.
はい、ということでね センター画面とかみんな「おー！ジャスティス！」…盛り上がってますけども。
Alright, so everyone looking at the center screen is like, "Oh! Justice!"... things are getting hyped.
それでは皆さん、そろそろね、うん。
Well then everyone, soon, yeah.
次の曲行くか！行くよ？
Shall we go to the next song? Here we go?
やめだ！
Never mind!
はい、タジタジに…焦らないでください！
Yes, flustered... Don't rush!
タジタジに、しないでくださいよ！
Don't make us flustered!
はい、ということでですね、じゃあ息整えて、いいですか？
Alright, so everyone, catch your breath, is that okay?
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
それではですね、そろそろ次の曲を紹介したいと思います。皆さんが待ち望んだ、この…コラボレーション楽曲です！
Well then, we'd like to introduce the next song. This is the collaboration song you've all been waiting for!
それではご覧ください！
Now then, please take a look!
日清カレーメシ起死回生の一撃 コラボレーション楽曲、カレーメシ・ミラクル！
Nissin Curry Meshi's comeback strike collaboration song, Curry Meshi Miracle!
お湯を入れて秘伝のルーを まてろまてろ 混ぜてとけたらカレーがドーン！
Pour in hot water, wait for the secret roux, wait, wait, mix it and when it dissolves, curry goes boom!
カレーカレー、カレーカレー、カレーメシでしょ！
Curry curry, curry curry, it's Curry Meshi!
めっちゃカレーが食べたい でも配信直前 これなんて大ピンチ 助けて！
I really want to eat curry, but the stream is starting right now, what a huge pinch, help me!
そんな私に救世主登場 黄色なあいつが黄色さ！
A savior appears for someone like me, that yellow guy's yellowness!
カレーカレー、カレーカレー、カレーメシでしょ！
Curry curry, curry curry, it's Curry Meshi!
カレーカレー、カレーカレー、カレーメシ参上！
Curry curry, curry curry, Curry Meshi arrives!
お湯を入れて たった五分で 本当に 本当に カレーなんて作れるの？
Pour in hot water, in just five minutes, can you really, really make curry like that?
フタを開けて シャバシャバでも まぜろまぜろ ひたすら混ぜろ
Open the lid, even if it's watery, mix, mix, mix away!
本当にカレーになってきた！
It's really turning into curry!
いっさ ミラクルくるくるクルミニシ カレーメシ
One, two, miracle, spin, spin, spin, Nissin Curry Meshi
レス ミラクルくるくるクルおイシ カレーの真実
Less, miracle, spin, spin, spin, delicious truth of curry
スパイス詰め込んだ
Packed with spices
こだわりの味
A flavor crafted with care
大満足 復活でしょ！
Ultimate satisfaction, a comeback!
日清カレーメシ
Nissin Curry Meshi
しゅばぞく作れてうまいっしょ！
Shuba-zoku can make it and it's delicious!
カレーでこういうこの手こよ！
With curry, this is how you do it!
普通においしいよ
It's normally delicious!
みんなでいっせのーで
Everyone ready, set, go
カレーメシだって即席とは思えないほどコクのある…
Curry Meshi has such rich flavor you wouldn't expect from instant...
踏み込みあっちのバリエーションも豊富だからいつまでも無限にいけちゃう！
And the variations are so rich you can keep going infinitely!
カレーカレー、カレーカレー、カレーメシでしょ！
Curry curry, curry curry, it's Curry Meshi!
カレーカレー、カレーカレー、カレーメシ参上！
Curry curry, curry curry, Curry Meshi arrives!
電子レンジも お鍋もいらない 本当に本当に お湯だけいれれば大丈夫！
No microwave or pot needed, as long as you add hot water, it's all good!
即席食品の てっぺんめざし
Aimed at the top of instant foods
まぜろ、まぜろ、ひたすら、まぜろ！
Mix, mix, mix away!
本当にカレーができちゃった！
Curry is really done!
いっさ ミラクルくるくるクルミニシ カレーメシ
One, two, miracle, spin, spin, spin, Nissin Curry Meshi
レス ミラクルくるくるクルサイコ 感じちゃうキミとボク
Less, miracle, spin, spin, spin, feeling awesome, you and me
たまねぎの旨みと
With the umami of onions
確信的な
And a definite
止まらないおいしさがイエス！日清カレーメシ
Unstoppable deliciousness is yes! Nissin Curry Meshi
カレーカレー、カレーカレー、カレーメシでしょ！
Curry curry, curry curry, it's Curry Meshi!
最先端のカレーでGO！
Go with cutting-edge curry!
いっさ ミラクルくるくるクルミニシ カレーメシ…
One, two, miracle, spin, spin, spin, Nissin Curry Meshi...
さあ ミラクル くるくるくるに しーカレーメシ！
Come on, miracle, spin spin spin, see Curry Meshi!
もっと ミラクル くるくるくるがーしょ いただきます！
Even more miracle, spin spin spin, let's eat!
いっさ ミラクル くるくるくるに しーカレーメシ！
Issah! Miracle, spin spin spin, see Curry Meshi!
めっさ ミラクル くるくるくるおいしーカレーも信じた！
Messah! Miracle, spin spin spin, I even believed in delicious curry!
本当の呪いに
To a true curse,
細さ満身で
with all my might,
大満足をしたいでしょ？
don't you want to be fully satisfied?
日清カレーメシ！
Nissin Curry Meshi!
カレー食べ！カレー食べ！カレーメシでしょ？
Eat curry! Eat curry! Isn't it Curry Meshi?
はーい！ということで！
Alright! So,
お届けしたのは日清カレーメシとホロライブのコラボレーション楽曲、「カレーメシ・イン・ミラクル」でしたー！
what we just brought you was the collaboration song between Nissin Curry Meshi and Hololive, "Curry Meshi in Miracle"!
イェーーイ！
Yaaay!
いやもうね、心臓死にそうですけど！
Man, my heart feels like it's gonna stop!
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
心臓が…心臓がやばい！
My heart... My heart is beating so fast!
がんばりよ！がんばりよ！
Hang in there! Hang in there!
「カレーメシ・イン・ミラクル」はですね、お願いマッスルやでおなじみ、烏屋茶房さん、篠崎あやとさん作編曲によるオリジナル楽曲でぇーす！
"Curry Meshi in Miracle" is an original song composed and arranged by Urayama-san and Ayato Shinozaki, known for "Onegais Muscle"!
イェーーイ！ありがとうございます！
Yaaay! Thank you so much!
アニメっぽさを前面に出し、耳に残るフレーズによる中毒性の高い楽曲となっております！
It's a highly addictive song featuring anime-style vibes and catchy phrases that stick in your ear!
確かに、すごい中毒性が高い曲だよね。
True, it's a super addictive song.
なんかもう無限に…
It's like endlessly...
これだって、あの、配信中とかもなんか「カレーカレー」ってコメント流れるとさ、歌っちゃう！
Even during streams, when comments like "Curry Curry" scroll by, I end up singing it!
歌っちゃう！それ中毒性がすごいんだよね。
You end up singing it! The addictiveness is real.
ねぇ、本当に！
Right, totally!
ちょっとね、この曲ね、あ、みなさんもね、可愛い！
And you guys are so cute singing this song too!
そしてですね、なんとですね、今！
And guess what, right now!
カレーメシスパイスライブがですね、Twitterトレンド1位を目指して、感想をツイートしよう！
The Curry Meshi Spice Live is aiming for #1 on Twitter trends! Let's tweet our thoughts!
どんどんいったいどんなものでもね、ガンガンつぶやいてください！
Tweet whatever comes to mind, go all out!
お願いします！これです、これこれこれ。
Please do! Here it is, right here.
ちなみにスパ、この曲で好きなのは…
By the way, my favorite part in this song is...
「混ぜろ！」
"Mix it!"
ここね！もうめっちゃめちゃ好きなんですけど…
Right here! I love this part so much...
お二人間、この曲どういうところが好きとかありますか？フブとか？
Do you guys have any favorite parts in this song? Fubu-chan?
そうだね、まあ例えば、うーん…
Let's see, well for example, um...
ま、これもう良かったし…
Well, this part was also good...
あーここね！ここね！ここね！
Ah, right here! Right here! Right here!
ここもね、結構ね、あの特徴的な振り付けなさ…
This part also has quite a distinctive choreography...
特徴的な振り付けをする所が…
The choreography is so distinctive...
すごい可愛いんだよね！アリガト！アリガト！
It's so cute! Thank you! Thank you!
全力でポーズをキメてでね！
Striking a pose with all our might!
なんかさ、あとさ、せっかくだからさ、3人でポーズ撮りたくないですか？
Also, since we're here, don't you want the three of us to pose together?
ちょっとね！あ、そうさ、せっかくだからさ…
Let's do it! Since we have the chance...
3人で、ちょっとね、ポーズ撮りたくないですか？
Wouldn't it be fun to strike a pose together?
あー撮って！もう撮って！
Ah, take it! Take pictures already!
ちゃんとダイスがあって大丈夫！
Make sure you get good dice shots, it's fine!
じゃあね、まずいつもので行きますね。
Alright, let's start with our usual one.
ここからね。
From here.
じゃみんなスクショタイムですよ！
Alright everyone, it's screenshot time!
じゃあ、せーの、ジャスティス！
Ready, set, Justice!
これね、たくさんね、撮ってください！
Please take lots of screenshots!
頼むぴこ！頼むぞ！
Count on you, Piko! Count on you!
いつまでやるの、これ！
How long are we gonna hold this pose?!
次の次！
Next one, next one!
あ、ジャスティス、キメポーズもね、あります！ありがとうございます！
Ah, Justice, there's also a finishing pose! Thank you very much!
いやちょっともうね、30分吸っただけでね…
Man, after holding our breath for 30 minutes...
ちょっと次の曲にもね、行きたいと思うんですけどね。
We'd like to move on to the next song, but...
テンポ早いからみんなお水とか大丈夫？
The tempo is fast, so is everyone okay on water?
ちょっと飲んだ方がいいよ。
You should drink some water.
素直に人には見えるやつ、あそうそう、変な人には見えないやつね。
Honestly, the kind people can see... Ah right, the kind invisible people can't see.
まだまだこれからね、ここから結構大変ですから！
We've still got a long way to go, it gets pretty tough from here!
立ち位置ね、ついてくださいよー！
Make sure you get in position!
はい、それではですね、立ち位置ね、ついてくださいよー！
Alright then, please take your positions!
よーい！
Ready!
それでは、コラボレーション楽曲のお披露目はここまでなんですが！
Well then, the reveal of our collaboration song ends here, but!
ここからは、スパたち…
From here on, our spice...
スパイスラブによる
Brought to you by Spice Love,
ふぁーーー！？
Whaaa!?
このライブ楽曲を立て続けにお送りしたいと思います！
We'll be delivering these live songs back-to-back!
来た来た！
It's here, it's here!
それではね、ぜひ2曲続けてご覧ください。
Now then, please enjoy two songs in a row.
キラキラだぁ、そして、夢見るステージ！！
It's so sparkly... and the dream-filled stage!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best times, with the best friends,
キラメキに乗って☆ (イエーイ！)
Ride on the sparkle☆ (Yeah!)
ライブはまだまだ終わらない
The live show isn't over yet!
このライブもまだまだ終わらない 続いてきてね！
This live isn't over yet either, keep following us!
覚えているかな？最初の歌
Do you remember? The very first song
私、声が震えていた
My voice was trembling
(ほんの少し)
(Just a little bit)
あの日から続く未来は
The future continuing from that day
みんなで掴んだ今日だよ
Is today that we all grasped together!
もっともっともっともっともっともっと 加速するハート (一緒に)
Accelerating our hearts more and more and more... (Together!)
行くよどこまでも
Let's go anywhere!
(Are you ready?)
準備はOK？
Are you ready?
ひらけ！！夢の扉を (1, 2, 3)
Open!! The door of dreams (1, 2, 3)
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best times, with the best friends,
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
We're right here, because you found us!
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
We came wanting to meet you, let's sing together!
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って☆
Riding an endless melody and sparkle☆
届いているかな？ 私の声 (ハッキリと)
Is it reaching you? My voice (Clearly)
届けたいのは君に笑顔 (そのスマイル)
What I want to deliver to you is a smile (That smile)
届いてるかな？ 私の声 (あぁ君と)
Is it reaching you? My voice (Ah, with you)
届けたいのは君に笑顔 (望む未来)
What I want to deliver to you is a smile (The future we hope for)
リズムの向こう さみしくって (悔しくて)
Beyond the rhythm, feeling lonely (And frustrated)
みんなとなら泣かれない
With everyone, I won't cry!
ぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっと 全て抱きしめて (一緒に)
Hugging everything tightly, tightly, tightly... (Together!)
行こうどこまでも (Are you ready?)
Let's go anywhere! (Are you ready?)
準備はOK？
Are you ready?
すすめ！希望の道を (1, 2, 3)
Advance! Down the path of hope (1, 2, 3)
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
好きな気持ちカラフルに奏でたいんだ
I want to play my favorite feelings colorfully!
最高の場所 最高のみんなと
In the best place, with the best everyone!
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
We're right here, it's not an illusion!
君の心が幸せに染まるように
So that your heart is dyed in happiness,
重ねてくハーモニー キラメキ纏って☆
Layering our harmony, wrapped in sparkle☆
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな そんな願いわがままでもいいでしょ？
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing, is a selfish wish like that alright?
だって楽しくてもうとまらない
Because it's so fun, I can't stop anymore!
輝くステージでもっともっと (お願い！)
On this shining stage, more and more (Please!)
ずっと (おー！イエーイ！)
Forever! (Ou! Yeah!)
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけじゃ語れない
Words like happy, fun, and beloved aren't enough to describe it
今も今もある悩みはあるけど
Even now, even now, I still have worries, but
ここにいるよ 私ここにいるよ
We're right here, I'm right here!
君と同じ世界を見つめて (行くよ？)
Gazing at the same world as you (Shall we go?)
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best times, with the best friends,
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
We're right here, because you found us!
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう (せーのっ！)
We came wanting to meet you, let's sing together! (Ready, set!)
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って☆
Riding an endless melody and sparkle☆
キラメキ纏って☆ (イエーイ！)
Wrapped in sparkle☆ (Yeah!)
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけじゃ語れない
Words like happy, fun, and beloved aren't enough to describe it
今も今もある悩みはあるけど
Even now, even now, I still have worries, but
ここにいるよ 私ここにいるよ 君と同じ世界を
We're right here, I'm right here, gazing at the same world as you!
見つめて (行くよ！)
Gazing (Let's go!)
見つめていけよ！キラメキライダー☆
Keep gazing! Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best times, with the best friends,
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
We're right here, because you found us!
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
We came wanting to meet you, let's sing together!
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って☆
Riding an endless melody and sparkle☆
キラメキ纏って☆ (イエーイ！)
Wrapped in sparkle☆ (Yeah!)
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って☆
Riding an endless melody and sparkle☆
キラメキ纏って☆
Wrapped in sparkle☆
かさねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Holding our joined hands tightly without letting go,
行くよ 行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go, let's head to the sky of our dreams!
窓越しに見上げた
Looking up through the window,
とても小さな空 ここで出会えたのは
the sky was so small. Meeting you right here
数え切れない奇跡 繰り返したい人たちが
is a miracle beyond count, a bond we want to repeat.
白めきを繋いで 星のような笑顔で
Connecting our sparkles with smiles like stars,
スペース バイ スペース 名前の声が力になる
Space by space, your voices give me strength.
スペース バイ スペース ここでそれぞれ目指すもの
Space by space, what each of us aims for here—
それぞれ描くもの それぞれ願い叶う夢へ
what each depicts, towards dreams where wishes come true.
かさねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Holding our joined hands tightly without letting go,
一人ひとり違う色で動き出すストーリー
a story begins to move with each person's unique colors.
塗りむくことなくまっすぐに
Stretching straight without any unevenness,
行くよ 行こう 夢見る空へ
let's go, let's head to the sky of our dreams!
笑い合ったことや 過ぎ去りない話題
Times we laughed together, topics that won't fade away—
思い出いっぱいな上に ああ そういう毎日の日々
Though full of memories, ah, days like these
古臭くなくって 名前つけて保存 誰よりも大事に生き生きと
never get old; save them with a name, living vibrantly more than anyone.
おうおう 今日も賑やかすぎくらいに 笑顔が止まらない
Oh oh, today is lively enough to make our smiles unstoppable.
思いは膨らんでいく 重ねた今 ギュッと噛み締めた
Feelings keep expanding; the present we overlapped, we savored tightly.
一人ひとり違う声で 遠くへと サーの声は広がる 手をかざしたらまっすぐに行くよ
With each person's different voice echoing far away, our voices spread. If we hold our hands up straight, let's go—
行くよ 行こう 夢見る空へ
let's go, let's head to the sky of our dreams!
憧れ手を伸ばし ついに届いた その光が いつのか また誰かの憧れに変わる
Reaching our hands out in longing, it finally reached us—that light turning into someone else's longing someday.
繋げよう
Let's connect them!
かさねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Holding our joined hands tightly without letting go,
一人ひとり違う色で 動き出すストーリー
a story begins to move with each person's unique colors.
出会えたすべてにありがとう
Thank you for everything we've encountered.
奇跡たって起こし続け ずっとずっとそばにいるよ
Continuing to create miracles, we'll stay by your side forever and ever.
行くよ 行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go, let's head to the sky of our dreams!
はい！ということで二曲立て続けにお送りしたのはキラキラアイランドと夢見る空でしたー！
Yes! So, the two songs we delivered back-to-back were "Kirakira Island" and "Yumemiru Sora"!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
いやー、ほんとにいい曲ですねー！ちゃんとね、振り付けも...
Man, these really are such great songs! We even properly did the choreography...
振り返ってね、あったのはね、
Looking back, the one we had...
今日！今回が初めてなんですよう！
Today! This is our very first time!
みんなもね パチパチ
Everyone was clapping,
え、エモエモのエモだったしね！
it was super emotional!
エモいね！ありがとうございました！
So emotional! Thank you very much!
ということでですね、10月1日に始まった
So, the Curry Meshi WEEK
このカレーメシWEEKも今日で最終日！
that started on October 1st is on its final day!
もう終わっちゃうんだよね、
It's already ending.
お披露目発表会からたくさんの曲が目白押しだったと思うんですが、皆さんどうでしたか？
There were so many songs since the reveal event, how was it for everyone?
よかった！よかった！
It was great! It was great!
どうだった？
How was it?
もうね、最高ってね！
It was simply the best!
そうか、そうだよなってね、みんなね思ってますけれども、あ、そうだ
Right, you guys must be thinking that too. Oh, that's right.
なんとですね、あのツイートトレンド2位までいったんだって！
And guess what? Our Twitter trend reached #2!
みんなやったね！やった！やった！頑張った！
Everyone, we did it! We did it! We worked hard!
この調子でもっと盛り上げてください！
Please keep the excitement going like this!
そしてですね、あの、まだね、ライブはまだ終わりじゃないですから、
And also, the live stream isn't over yet,
皆さんね、最後まで楽しみにしといてください！
so everyone, please look forward to it until the very end!
それではね、企画の方ね、まず振り返っていきたいと思います！
Now, let's look back at the events first!
まずお披露目発表会がありましたね！ありました、あったね。
First, there was the reveal presentation! Yes, there was, that's right.
スバルはね、軽率にカレーを食べてたってツイートが多かったって思ったんですけど、
I thought there were a lot of tweets saying Subaru was casually eating curry,
どうでしたか、あくあちゃん？
How about you, Aqua-chan?
いやあ、もうね、本当にお披露目は楽しかったんだけど、私は、
Well, the reveal was really fun, but for me,
忙しくても料理が下手くそでも、すぐに食べれるよってアピールにぴったりだよって選ばれたんだけど。
I was chosen because it perfectly appeals that you can eat it easily even if you're busy or bad at cooking.
本当にね、カレーメシ食べたら本当に手軽だったでしょ？ねえ！
Really, eating Curry Meshi made things so convenient, right? Right?
めちゃめちゃ手軽になったでしょ？
It became super convenient, didn't it?
そして、やっぱカレーメシにはニンジンが入ってるペコだからって
And, since Curry Meshi has carrots in it, peko...
なんか言ってますね！
She says something like that!
カレーメシにはニンジンが入ってるペコだからって選ばれたペコでしょ？
You were chosen because Curry Meshi has carrots in it, right?
あんたたちに聞いたほうがいいんじゃない？
Shouldn't you ask yourselves?
あんたたちどうだった？
How was it for you guys?
なんとね、PRできてました！できてた？
Believe it or not, we were able to do PR! You were?
よかった、よかった！
Great, great!
いいですね。
That's good.
でもなんかクサって…
But why does it smell like grass...
そしてですね、チョコ先生のちょこっとクッキングがありましたね！
And then, Chocotto Cooking by Choco-sensei took place!
そう、この配信の中でもたくさんいろんなレシピが紹介されてるので、皆さんぜひ見てみてください！
Yes, many different recipes are introduced in this stream too, so please check them out!
そして次にあったのはホログラカレーメシスペシャル！
And next was the Hologra Curry Meshi Special!
ということでですね、ホログラなんとですね、カレーメシスペシャル版が史上最大カットで作られていますので、ぜひそちらもですね、チェックしてみてください！
That's right, the Hologra Curry Meshi Special edition is created with the largest cut in history, so please be sure to check that out too!
ええ、ということでですね、そしてその昨日ですね、味変選手権もありました！
And so, yesterday there was also the Flavor Change Championship!
皆さんね、たくさんのね、あの投稿ありがとうございました！
Thank you everyone for all the submissions!
なんと投稿総数は626個！
The total number of submissions was 626!
すごーい！ありがとうございました！
That's amazing! Thank you very much!
この中でね、皆さんね、あのいろんなね、味変楽しみ。そしてこちらね！
Everyone is looking forward to various flavor changes here. And this one!
ちょっと待ってくれよ、これどういうこと？トマトジュースでした？
Wait a second, what is this? Tomato juice?
どういうことってこと？初めて肉じゃがねってことなの？
What do you mean? Does that mean meat and potatoes for the first time?
はい、ということでね、こちらもね、楽しくできてると思うので、ぜひ皆さんね、チェックしてみてください！
Yes, so this one turned out fun as well, so please make sure to check it out!
そして、引き続いてカレーメシよろしくお願いしますということでですね、現在実施中のですね、ホロあのリツイートキャンペーンもいよいよ最終日！
And please continue to support Curry Meshi! Also, the ongoing RT campaign is finally in its final hours!
スパイスライブこの3人のですね、直筆サイン入り特製ポスターを10名様にプレゼント！
We are giving away special posters with handwritten autographs of the three of us to 10 people!
そう、皆さんね、カレーメシくんの公式Twitterをフォローして、対象となる投稿をリツイートするだけで応募できちゃうようになっています！
That's right! Just follow Curry Meshi-kun's official Twitter and retweet the target post to enter!
締め切りは10月19日月曜日明日の23時59分まで！
The deadline is tomorrow, Monday, October 19th at 11:59 PM!
詳しくはカレーメシくんの公式Twitterをチェック！
Check Curry Meshi-kun's official Twitter for details!
もうなんか、頭がもう真っ白で……
My mind is completely blank...
もうさっきから汗やばいのよ！
I've been sweating like crazy since earlier!
でもね、本当に楽しかったね！
But really, it was so much fun!
ねえ！終わったねみんな！
Yeah! It's over, everyone!
よかったよ！大丈夫？
It was great! Are you okay?
大丈夫、大丈夫！まだね、あるからね！
It's okay! We still have more to go!
でも最初さ、めっちゃめちゃ緊張してたじゃん！
But at first, we were super nervous, weren't we?
こうやってやってたら、10分前ぐらいにやばくない？って。
Doing this, about 10 minutes before, saying 'Isn't this crazy?'
おはようございまーす！
Good morning!
こんぐらっちゅれーしょん、みたいな感じでね
Like a "Congratulations!" sort of vibe,
そうだね、皆さんね、ぜひね、最後まで楽しんでいってもらいたい！
That's right! Everyone, we really want you to enjoy it right to the end!
そしてね、どんどんツイートしてもらいたい！お願いしまーす！お願いしまーす！
And we want you to tweet as much as you can! Please! Please!
ペコラは緊張するからね
Pekora gets nervous, you know.
いや、本当緊張したってことだよね
Yeah, that means you were really nervous, right?
でもはじまっちゃうそう！なんか、もうなんていうんだろ、みんなの勢いもあるってことだし、なんか楽しくなっちゃって
But it just gets so exciting! With everyone's energy, it just got so fun,
おっぺこー、おっぺこーってずっとさ、こうやってさ、うわーって
going "Oppe-ko, oppe-ko" the whole time like, "Whoa!"
でもお手々ポーズもね！やれたね！
But we managed the hand pose too! We did it!
でも30分までの
But until 30 minutes--
そう、30分、30分までずっと、やばいかもしれない！大丈夫、大丈夫、大丈夫、みたいなさ
Right, 30 minutes, until 30 minutes it was like, "This might be bad!"
そうそうそうそう、みたいなね！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, just like that!
皆さんね、コメントでね、ありがとー！
Everyone, thank you so much in the comments!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
おっぺこーってまだ終わってないからね！まだあるからね！
"Oppe-ko" isn't over yet! There's still more!
すばるちゃんさ、やってみたかったことがあるんだよね
Subaru-chan, you said there was something you wanted to try, right?
そう、あのね、二人でねハート作ってほしくって、こういうことやんの？
Yeah, so, I wanted the two of you to make a heart with me, like this?
あ、そうそうそう！あ、できる？
Ah, yeah, yeah! Oh, can you do it?
わあ！おっぺこー！かわいい！
Wow! Oppe-ko! Cute!
色合いがさ、すごくさ、きれいだからさ
The color scheme is just so pretty, so
あ、いいぺこー！
Ah, nice Peko!
ね、たくさんね、皆さんね、ツイートしてください！
Everyone, please tweet a lot!
いいよね、これ！いいぺこ、いいぺこ！スパイスラブのポーズをね、考えてね
Isn't this great? Nice Peko, nice Peko! Thinking of the Spice Love pose,
考えてね
thinking of it
あ！スパイスラブ！ラブ、ラブ、ラブ！スパイスラブ！
Ah! Spice Love! Love, love, love! Spice Love!
めちゃいいじゃん、これ！い、いいよね、そう！
This is so good! It's, it's great, yeah!
ということでね、それでは早いもので、もうね、次で最後の曲でーす！
And with that, before you know it, it's already time for our final song!
えーー！
Ehーー!
みんなね、やだやだ、やっていこー！やってください！
Everyone, no way, let's keep going! Do it!
最後の曲ですよ、最後の曲！やっていこー！はい！
It's the final song, the final song! Let's go! Yes!
それではね、最後までみんな、盛り上がっていってほしいでーす！
So everyone, we want you to keep the hype going right to the end!
ということで、それでは最後、今回の企画のようにこれからも笑顔で楽しく！シャイニースマイルストーリーです！
And with that, finally, just like this project, smiling and having fun from now on! It's "Shiny Smily Story"!
朝日昇るまで 空は僕らだけ
Until the morning sun rises, the sky is just for us.
どこへまでも行こう あの夢手に入れたい
Let's go anywhere, I want to get that dream.
それとそれ 誓った 心って
Each and every sworn heart
走れど
though I run—
次はいよいよ最後の曲だよ！みんな最後までついてきてね！
Next is finally our final song! Everyone, keep up with us till the end!
じっと見てもまもなく見えな場所に目覚めてた
Waking up in a place where soon nothing can be seen,
ほんの小さな希望に この瞳奪われた
these eyes were stolen by a tiny hope.
座って揺れる心も上手く宙に沈めて この小さな勇気をもぎ絞っていたよ
Even a swaying heart, sinking smoothly into the air, I was squeezing out this tiny courage.
諦めの文字 手を伸ばして進む 苦しい時も もう私は
Words of resignation, reaching out and moving forward, even in painful times, I am no longer
一人じゃないから
alone anymore!
だかもっと夢追いかけたい ワクワク止まらない 外を越えてく 世界に見せてあげる
That's why I want to chase my dreams even more, thrills won't stop, crossing the outside, I'll show the world!
アップデートしてみたい こんなん何処想定しない
I want to try updating, something like this I never expected!
それとそれ 誓った 心って 走れど
And each one, a sworn heart, though I run--
碧の空に輝くまぶしい思いは 見たことのない光を リアルに届けるよ
Dazzling feelings shining in the blue sky, delivering unprecedented light to reality!
いつも聞こえるエールは ここにキャプチャーして また新しい光を探したくなるよ
The cheers I always hear are captured right here, making me want to search for a new light!
君の笑顔は心地よく進む 悲しい時に見返すよ 力が湧くから
Your smile makes me progress comfortably, I'll look back at it when sad, because it gives me strength!
胸を張って 夢追いかけたい 奇跡のステージに 一緒につくろう
Chest puffed out, I want to chase dreams, let's create a miraculous stage together!
終わらない夢を 誰一人たがせない 愛はまったくこの世界
An endless dream, we won't let anyone be left alone, love is totally in this world!
それとそれ 違った 宝物で 色どれ
And each one different, colored with treasures!
今日はライブに来てくれてありがとう！これからもカレーメシとホロライブもよろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much for coming to the live today! Please continue to support Curry Meshi and Hololive!
悲しい時も 寂しい時も
Even when we're sad, even when we're lonely,
分け合えるものがある
there's something we can share together.
忘れずに この鼓動 鳴らし続けたい
I want to keep this heartbeat ringing without forgetting it.
終わらない 世界に溢れ出すよ
Overflowing into an endless world,
笑顔たち
those smiles!
憧れの舞台に立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams,
熱く輝きたい
and shine brightly with passion.
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, and wanting to laugh together again.
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢を手にしたい
and hold that dream in my hands.
生み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Let's create the first step of a miracle!
息切れして 夢追いかけたい
Running out of breath, I want to chase my dreams.
ワクワクと止まらない 想像を超えてく
Thrill and excitement won't stop, surpassing imagination,
世界に見せてあげる
I'll show it to the world!
アクセスしてよね
Access it, okay?
後悔なんてここにない
There's no such thing as regret here.
それぞれ違った 心で作るわ
We make it with our different hearts.
スパイスライブ カレーメシWEEK
[Spice Live: Curry Meshi WEEK]